I've written a program that accepts applications for a library card.
كتبت برنامجاً يقبل طلبات تقدم للحصول على بطاقة مكتبة.
Library cards give you access to a lot of books you might want to read.
تعطيك بطاقات المكتبة إمكانية الوصول إلى العديد من الكتب التي قد تريد قراءتها.
And to apply for a card,
وللتقدم للحصول على بطاقة،
you need to show some form of identification.
عليك إظهار هوية شخصية من نوع ما.
This program accepts a passport,
يقبل هذا البرنامج جواز سفر
a birth certificate, or a driver's license as valid ID.
أو شهادة ميلاد أو رخصة قيادة كهوية شخصية صالحة.
And whether or not a person provides any of these is stored in these boolean variables,
وسواءً زود الشخص أي من هذه أم لا، يتم حفظها في هذه المتغيرات المنطقية،
passport, birthCertificate and driversLicense.
passport وbirthCertificate وdriversLicense.
And these are true if that kind of ID is given.
وتكون قيمها true إن تم تقديم هوية شخصية من ذلك النوع.
A person might provide multiple forms of ID or none at all.
قد يوفر شخص عدة أنواع من الهويات، أو لا يوفر أي هوية بتاتاً.
And this program will print out whether an ID is valid,
وسيقوم هذا البرنامج بطباعة ما إن كانت الهوية صالحة،
or if the ID is invalid,
أو إن كانت الهوية غير صالحة.
and then the application for a library card is denied.
عندها يتم رفض طلب الحصول على بطاقة مكتبة.
What will the output of this program be for the following boolean values?
ماذا سيكون مخرج هذا البرنامج للقيم المنطقية التالية؟
Passport equals false, birth certificate equals true,
"Passport = false" و"birth certificate = true".
and driver's license equals true.
و"driver's license = true".